Here's a list of colors and materials.
这是一张颜色和材料的清单.
If you ever want to match something,
如果你要配点什么,
take the list to the store.
可以带这张单子去店里买.
Thanks.
谢谢.
And here's your final invoice.
这是你最后的发票.
Fine. I can write a check now, if that's OK.
好的.我现在就可以开支票,如果没问题的话.
Bill, you're my favorite client.
Bill,你是我最喜欢的顾客.
I just wish I had more than two rooms for you to do.
我真希望我有超过两个房间可以请你们装潢.
Just call us when you have a house, OK?
等你有了大房子就给我们打电话,好吗?
I'm sure all your clients come back.
我相信你们所有的客户都会成为回头客.
All but one.
只有一个不是.
Oh, really? You have to tell me.
Oh,真的?这你得跟我讲讲.
I'm your favorite client.
我可是你们最喜欢的顾客.
He had no sense of color.
他对色彩没有一点感觉.
One day last summer, we got a call.
去年夏季的一天,我们接到个电话.
It was a doctor, a very successful surgeon
是一位医生,一位非常成功的外科医生
who wanted us to design his consulting offices.
他想请我们设计他的诊室.
And it was very important to the big surgeon...
对那位名医来说,有一点非常重要
Nan...
...that the colors be soothing.
色彩要让人感到平和、放松.
Well, that makes sense.
Well,有道理.
I had no problem with that.
对此我毫无异议.
However, the surgeon and my partner could not agree on green.
但是,那位外科医生与我的合伙人在绿色的问题上意见不一致.
Green is...green, right?
绿色就是绿色，对不对?
It was a very soft sea foam green,
是种非常柔和的海水泡沫般的绿色,
very gentle on the eyes.
有非常柔和的视觉效果.
What color is that?
那是什么颜色?
Green.
绿色.
Thank you.
谢谢.
Well, the surgeon said the green was yellowy-brown
Well,那位外科医生把那种绿色说成是黄褐色,
and not relaxing at all.
而且根本无法让人放松.
In fact, he said the green was...
事实上,他说那种绿色是...
what did he call it?
他怎么说来着?
Institutional. Do you believe it?
单调俗套的.你相信吗?
He gave me such a headache.
他让我如此头痛.
Green, yellow, green, yellow.
绿色,黄色,绿色,黄色.
We finally went with a shade of pink...
最后我们用了一种粉色...
Which he called violet.
他说那是紫色.
And the man is an eye surgeon!
这人居然是个眼外科医生!